hey everybody welcome to this b1 english
listening practice video
you can use this video to practice your
listening and comprehension
as i speak before we start remember to
subscribe to the channel
click on the bell and follow us on
instagram
you ready so today i'm going to talk
about
natural disasters this is an interesting
topic
because depending on where you live you
might have to deal with natural
disasters on a regular basis
let's go through some of the most
notable disasters that occur
throughout the world first let's talk
about earthquakes
for a lot of people this might just be
the scariest disaster
because it can strike at any moment
without any notice
that being said the vast majority of
earthquakes are minor and cause little
to no damage
as a california native i've obviously
witnessed my share of earthquakes but
i've only ever really experienced
one major earthquake it just so happens
that i was at the gym
and when the earthquake started all the
weights and machines
started shaking i was definitely a
little freaked out
but that's really the only time i've
been in a big earthquake
if you live in certain parts of the
world you might never have experienced
an earthquake in your whole life
for example my brazilian students
usually tell me that they've never been
in an earthquake before
but on the other hand my students from
chile and japan
tell me that they feel an earthquake
almost every week
for most of us that seems insane and
what about you
have you ever been in an earthquake
before okay so now let's talk about
hurricanes
hurricanes can be some of the most
destructive events imaginable
take hurricane katrina for instance this
category 5 hurricane
absolutely devastated the city of new
orleans and caused
almost 2 000 deaths and over 125 billion
dollars in damage
of course not all hurricanes are this
catastrophic
but all hurricanes cause some damage
when they hit
land thankfully i've never been affected
by a hurricane before since i'm from the
west coast of the u.s
which is never affected by hurricanes
but for people living on the south and
east coasts
these storms pose a constant threat i
can't imagine what it would feel like to
know that there's a hurricane headed
straight in my direction
i hope i never find out all right
another natural disaster that can cause
all kinds of damage is a tornado
tornadoes are a phenomenon that happen
in the middle of the u.s
in states like oklahoma kansas and
nebraska
where the landscape is really flat you
might have seen tornadoes featured in
american movies before
where the people have to take shelter
underground and wait for the tornado to
pass by their town
i'm glad that i've never gotten caught
in the path of a tornado before
alright one more natural disaster that
affects people
all over the world is floods floods can
happen
in all kinds of different places if you
live in a city that doesn't have a high
level of
infrastructure it's likely that you've
seen some flooding before
in mexico for example many parts of the
big cities
flood every time there's heavy rain the
parts of the city that are at a lower
altitude
become like lakes and rivers and drivers
have a hard time navigating
sometimes the cars just stop and wait
for the rain to subside and for the
water to clear out
as you can imagine the traffic becomes a
complete mess
i really hate the rainy season in mexico
because
all of this is a normal occurrence
floods may not be the scariest natural
disaster
but they can be a huge inconvenience and
they can become dangerous
which natural disaster seems the
scariest to you
alright that's all for today leave a
comment and tell me if you've ever
experienced a natural disaster
and remember to subscribe to the channel
click on the bell
and follow us on instagram for more
english tips and lessons
i'll see you next time
[Music]
you